

Oakville, ON, Canada

□(+1) 2892596430 | ☑ liuchew@shernet.sheridancollege.ca | # palmswill.github.io/react-resume2021/ | ☑ palmswill | 匝 williamliucs

Summary

2+ years React-based web developer with experiences in business management and sales campaigns on e-Commerce platforms with front-end knowledge such as React library, HTML5, CSS3 and back-end knowledge such as NodeJs, Express REST API, Amazon S3, Firebase and Google API. Currently studying at Sheridan College and looking for an internship focusing on modern web development.

Professional Experience _____

Tribute Window Coverings

Mississauga, Canada

SMART HOME PRODUCT SUPPORT MANAGEMENT

Nov. 2019 - Present

- Provided product support for mechanical products, created online instruction videos and product manual receiving over 80 % positive feedback and product sales was observed to increase by more than 10% in the same period.
- Technical supported the company, included computer set up, software problems encountered etc. Reduced the IT support cost per month by more than 20 %.

Taiwan Intelligence Service Corps

Taichung, S.Taiwan (Remote)

April 2019 - April 2021

ASSOCIATE ARCHITECTURE AND SYSTEM DESIGNER (CONTRACT)

- Improved performance by redesigning database and created and modify user interface.
- · Created and modify user interface ,use cases and user flow design by communicating with the clients
- · Created detailed user manuals and release including issues and bug tracking

Tribute Window Coverings

Mississauga, Canada

WAREHOUSE & SUPPLY CHAIN MANAGEMENT

November 2017- November 2019

- Generated daily sales and inventory report, estimated the needed purchase based on report status. Accurately predicted sales trend preventing over or shortage of stock reducing department back-order rate by 20% in 2018 compared to previous years.
- · In charge of communication between vendors. Negotiated the price and brought down the cost of products for more than 10%.

Skills

Languages: JavaScript ES6,HTML5,CSS3,Java

Front End Libraries & Tools: ReactJ(Router, Redux Toolkit, Context API etc), Semantic UI, Bootstrap

Back Ends: NodeJs, Amazon S3, Google API, Firebase, Auth0

Others: Data analysis,Tech Support,Database Design, Microsoft Office,ERP,Quickbook

Projects

TWC E-Commerce Project (In Progress)

HTTPS://E-WEBSITE-TCC.HEROKUAPP.COM/

July. 2021 - Present

- An E-Commerce website that is built for online ordering for Tribute Window Coverings.
- A React front end website cooperating with ERP database, Amazon S3 image cloud and auth0 authentication.

Spacetagram

HTTP://NASAPOD2021.HEROKUAPP.COM/

September,2021

- A responsive NASA picture of the day liker.
- Built with React front-end, Semantic UI & NASA POD API.

The Shoppies

HTTPS://MOVIECHALLENGE2021.HEROKUAPP.COM/

April,2021

- A shareable movie nominator website.
- Built with React front end, Semantic UI and Movie IMDB API.

Education

Sheridan College

Oakville, Canada

Sep. 2020 - April. 2023

Software Development & Network Engineering (GPA:3.6/4)

• Relevant Courses: Enterprise Java, Web Programming, Interactive User Design, UX/UI Design

NOVEMBER 2, 2021 WILLIAM LIU · RÉSUMÉ